A Guide to the American Society of International Law records, Howard M. Holtzmann papers FA1872
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Writings, II; 15.66 Cubic Feet 29 legal document boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes
  - The Papers of Howard M. Holtzmann, 1969-2010; 1
    - Speech Materials - Book 1 - International Arbitration Rules of the World Arbitration Institute, Third Draft, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Speech Materials - Book 1 - Stella Eulogy, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Adoption of a New Egyptian Arbitration Law, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Should Bermuda's International Arbitration Law be Changed, If So, How, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Appendix A - UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - ICCA - Permanent Court of Arbitration Mutual Cooperation Agreement between Permanent Court of Arbitration at the Hague and International Council for Commercial Arbitration, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - The Desolate Wilderness, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Commencement, Jewish Theological Seminary of America, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - International Arbitration 60 Years On, A Look at the Future, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Address by HMH at the Signing of the Agreement Establishing a Model Clause for Arbitration in Vienna of Disputes in US-East German Trade, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Optional Arbitration Clause for Use in Contracts in USA-USSR Trade, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - American Community Council Thanksgiving Day Service, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Constitution Day Dinner Remarks, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Outline of Panel Discussion of Arbitration Rules and Institutions, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - A Message from HMH at the Dinner Honoring Prentis Hale on his retirement from the Syntex Board of Directors, undated (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "The Growth of a World-Wide Community of Arbitration", undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "First Session - Far Eastern Countries", undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Donald Memorial Address, undated (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "The Conduct of Arbitral Proceedings", undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - HMH Introduction Working Group 3, undated (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "The Role of Dispute Resolution in Facilitating International Trade and Investment", undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "Administrating Institution", undated (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "International Business and Law in Asia and the Pacific", Conference Time-Line, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "Five Ways the American Arbitration Association Can Assist in Resolving Disputes in Trade with the Soviet Union", undated (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "The London Embassy", undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "Code of Ethics for Arbitrators in Commercial Disputes", undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - "The Importance of Choosing the Right Place to Arbitrate an International Case", 1972 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - News and Notes from the Institute for Transnational Arbitration, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Iran-US Claims Tribunal Resignation Letter, undated (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Correspondence with Harold Hongju Koh, 2010 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - The Peacemaker Award, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - DeForest Prize, undated (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Speech Materials - Book 2 - Correspondence, 2003-2006 (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Recent Developments in Resolving International Commercial Disputes, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Dispute Resolution under the UNCITRAL Conciliation Rules, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - American Community Council Thanksgiving Day Service, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Remarks of HMH at Signing of Agreement Between the American Arbitration Association, the Polish Chamber of Commerce and the Federal Economic Chamber of Austria, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - What an Arbitrator Can Do to Overcome Delays in International Arbitration, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Whether, When, Where, and How to Arbitrate International Cases, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Hypothetical Case for Use in a Comparative Study of Arbitration Practice in Various Legal Systems, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Current Issues in International Commercial Arbitration, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      Including Lessons from the Iran-US Claims Tribunal
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - The Peace Palace, Home of Arbitration, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - An Introduction to the UNCITRAL Model Law, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - The Geopolitics of Arbitration, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Some Lessons from the Awards of the Iran-US Claims Tribunal that may be useful in Disputes Concerning the Termination of Joint Ventures, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Bologna Lecture Fact-Finding, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - International Bar Association Biennial Conference, New York, Introduction to Session II, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Resolving High-Tech Contractual Disputes in Europe after 1990 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Commemorative Tribute to Dr. Albert Bowers, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - "George", 1993 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - "Iran-US Claims Tribunal - It's Lessons for International Business Lawyers", undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - "How Effective Dispute Resolution Procedures Help to Facilitate International Trade and Investment", undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Dispute Resolution in Europe Under the UNCITRAL Conciliation Rules, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Iran-US Claims Tribunal - Memorandum, "Comments on Swiss Working Paper for Valletta Meeting", 1990 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Polytechnic Preparatory Country Day School Special Reunion Remarks, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - Bologna Program on Interim Measures, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - "Stella", undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - "Course of Study Outline", undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - "Adoption of a New Egyptian Arbitration Law", 1992 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - HMH Papers - Originals - Vol I - "The Conduct of the Arbitral Proceeding - Standards of Behavior of Arbitrators", 1988 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - HMH Papers - Scan Project Index, 2011 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - HMH Papers - Volume I, 1969-1975 (Box 22, Folder 26, Box 23, Folder 1-3)
    - HMH Papers - Volume II, 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
    - HMH Papers - Volume III, 1976-1979 (Box 23, Folder 6, Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    - HMH Papers - Volume IV, 1978-2010 (Box 24, Folder 3-6)
    - HMH Papers - Volume V, 1988-1991 (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
    - HMH Papers - Volume VI, 1992-1994 (Box 25, Folder 5-6)
    - HMH Papers - Personal Papers, 1977-1993 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - HMH Papers - General Papers, 1963-1977 (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    - HMH Papers - Tribute to the Blessed Memory of Rabbi Sandor Scheiber, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - HMH Papers - 42 Reunion Class Panel, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - HMH Papers - Resolving Disputes in US-China Trade, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - HMH Papers - The Lawyer as a Negotiator, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - HMH Papers - The Iran-US Claims Tribunal - Welcoming Addresses, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - HMH Papers - Report of the United States Delegation to UNCITRAL Working Group on International Contract Practices, 1982-1984 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - HMH Papers - Address Delivered by HMH at the Signing Ceremonies, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - HMH Papers - What an Arbitrator Can Do to Overcome Delays in International Arbitration, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - HMH Papers - The Work of the United States Claims Tribunal, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - HMH Papers - Introduction to ICCA, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - HMH Papers - Fact-Finding by the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - HMH Papers - Balancing the Need for Certainty and Flexibility in International Arbitration Procedures, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - HMH Papers - The Yale '42 Story, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Other Writings, 1974-2012; 2
    This subseries is largely comprised of essays, speeches, lectures, notes, interviews, and other public presentations. It also contains drafts, research materials, correspondence, and notes pertaining to several of Holtzmann's books, the "Code of Ethics for Arbitrators", "A Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration: Legislative History and Commentary". and "International Mass Claims Processes: Legal and Practical Perspectives", which he edited with Edda Kristjansdottir. Also of interest in this subseries are several light verses, satirical sketches, and fictional pieces written by Holtzmann, including "A Caribbean Christmas Carol", "Izzard Goes to Italy", and "The Wound and the Bow".
    - ABA-IBA-IABA, undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - "Advising Foreign Clients Doing Business in the USA" - Chapter, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - American Community Council Thanksgiving Day Service - Remarks by Howard M. Holtzmann, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Arbitration - An Indispensable Aid to Multinational Enterprise, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Arbitration as a Sloth, 1991-1993 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Arbitration in Long-Term Business Transactions, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - "Arbitrating International Commercial Cases in England - New Developments and Old Differences", 1976 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - "Arbitration and the Courts - Partners in A System of International Justice", 1978 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - "Arbitration of East-West Trade Disputes", 1974 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - "Arbitration - Rules, Laws, and Conventions", 1975-1977 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - ASIL Article, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - "Austria's Qualifications as the Venue for Arbitration in East-West Commercial Disputes", 2005 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - "Balancing the Need for Certainty and Flexibility in International Arbitration Procedures" - Proofs, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Bibliographies - "Bibliography on Arbitration", undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Bibliographies - Bibliography and Index - Floppy Disk, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Open for research - Access copy currently unavailabe. See a RAC archivist for further instruction.
    - Bibliographies - "Dispute Resolution Bibliography of Howard M. Holtzmann", 1994 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Bibliographies - List of Published Materials in the Offices of Holtzmann, Wise, and Shepard, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Biographies - For Abe, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Biographies - Yale, 2012 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Bulow Liber Amicorum - Chapter, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - "Can the Plausibility Standard of Proof Developed in Mass Claims Arbitration also be Useful in Commercial Cases", undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Caron Book - Chapter on Rules, 1981-1983 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - "A Caribbean Christmas Carol", undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - "The Centennial of the 1899 Peace Conference - The Roots of Today's Arbitration Culture", 1999 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Code of Ethics for Arbitrators - Drafts, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Code of Ethics for Arbitrators - Drafts, 1999-2001 (Box 28, Folder 9, Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Code of Ethics for Arbitrators - Revisions, 1999-2001 (Box 29, Folder 2-3, Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Comments Concerning Draft Optional Rules for Arbitration Involving International Organizations, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Comments Concerning Negotiations Between US Corporations and Soviet Foreign Trading Organizations, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Comments Concerning Remedy Questions in Back Pay Awards, and certain Procedural Problems in Arbitration, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Comments on the Third Draft of the International Arbitration Rules of the AAA's World Arbitration Institute, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Communication on "Arbitration and Contract Guidelines", 1972 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Comments on "International Arbitration Rules of the ABA", 1991 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Communication to First Working Party - The Relative Importance of Trade Usage in the UNCITRAL Rules, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Conciliation - A Promising Procedure for Resolving Multiparty Disputes, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Concluding Session - Russian Translation, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Constitution Day Dinner, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Council of Corporation Banking and Business Law - Meeting Reports, 1975-1980 (Box 30, Folder 5-7)
    - The Development of Evidentiary Procedures in International Commercial Arbitration Over the Last Twenty Years, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Dispute Resolution in Europe Under the UNCITRAL Conciliation Rules, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Efficient Organization of International Arbitrations, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Emergency Measures by Arbitrators Appointed by Institutions - Effectiveness and Enforceability, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - First Code of Ethics for Arbitrators in Commercial Disputes, undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Foundations of Modern Arbitration, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - The Geopolitics of Arbitration, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - "Great" Dictionary Entries, undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Guide to International Arbitration Under the Rules of the American Arbitration Association, undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Legislative History and Commentary - Background for Book, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Legislative History and Commentary - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Drafts - Article 7 and 35, 2011 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Drafts - Forward, Introduction, Arrangement of Book, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Drafts - "The Arrangement of this Book", undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Drafts - Introduction, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Drafts - Inscription for Copies of Book, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Drafts - Kluwer Contract, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Order Form, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Printed Material - Research Material, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Printed Material - Reviews, 1989-1994 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - HMH Lecture at Institute of Social Studies, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Holtzmann Papers Memo, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Holtzmann-Plotz Project, 2012 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - How Can Grievance Arbitration be Improved, undated (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - ICCA Seoul Conference, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - ILA Lecture, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - The Impact of Decisions and Practices of the Iran-USA Claims Tribunal on International Commercial Arbitration, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - The Indispensable Role of Libraries in Developing International Law, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - International Handbook on Commercial Arbitration - "United States", undated (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - International Congress of Arbitration - Communication, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - International Congress of Arbitration - Writings and Presentation, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - The Iran-US Claims Tribunal - It's Lessons for International Business Lawyers, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - "International Law - What it Is, What it Can Do, and What it Cannot Do", 1995 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - International Trade, Foreign Investment and the Rule of Law - The Use of Arbitration in Resolving Economic and Political Disputes, undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - American Arbitration Association, 2001-2003 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - CRPC (Bosnia), 2000-2005 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - Claims Resolution Tribunal I, 2001-2005 (Box 34, Folder 8-9)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - Claims Resolution Tribunal II, 2001-2002 (Box 34, Folder 10, Box 35, Folder 1)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - Claims Resolution Tribunal II and HVAP - Court Documents, 2001-2004 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - Claims Resolution Tribunal II and HVAP - Special Master's Interim Report, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 3-4)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - Eritrea-Ethiopia Claims Commission, 2001-2003 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - HPPC (Kosovo), 2000-2004 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - International Commission on Holocaust Era Insurance Claims, 1999-2005 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - IOM: GFLCP and HVAP, 2001-2004 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - Iran-US Claims Tribunal, 2002-2003 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - United Nations Compensation Commission, 1992-2005 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Background Documents - WIPO, 1999-2001 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Correspondence - General, 2005-2006 (Box 36, Folder 7-8)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Correspondence, Circular Letters, Agendae, Minutes, 2000-2005 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts, 2002 April (Box 37, Folder 3-5)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts, 2003 September (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts, 2005 December 12 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts - Introduction to Mass Claims Book, 2000-2005 (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts - Rovine Comments on Draft of Book - Part I, II, 2005 (Box 38, Folder 4-6)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts - Undated Draft with Corrections (Box 38, Folder 7, Box 39, Folder 1-3)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts - July 23 Redlined Draft, undated (Box 39, Folder 4-5)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts - Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 39, Folder 6-7)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts - Chapter 16 - James Castello, "UNCITRAL Rules", 2009 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Drafts - Summary - Table of Contents, 2005 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Offprints, 1997-2002 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Overview, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "International Mass Claims Processes" - Oxford University Press Agreement Drafts, 2004-2006 (Box 40, Folder 4-5)
    - Interviews - "Judge Howard Holtzmann Interview 001 - Lovett Productions", 2001 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Interviews - Leon Gortler, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - An Intro to the UNCITRAL Model Law, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Introduction of the Subjects of the Four Working Parties - English Original and French Translation, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Introduction, undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Introductory Note to the American Code of Ethics for Arbitrators in Commercial Disputes, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Izzard Goes to Italy, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "Jewish Life at Yale - Then and Now", 1992 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Jewish Theological Seminary of America Commencement - Remarks by Howard M. Holtzmann, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Judicial Application of the Convention on the Recognition and Enforcement of Foreign Arbitral Awards, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - The Key Choices in International Arbitration - Issues and Developments, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "Key Choices to be Made in Determining How to Resolve International Commercial Disputes", undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Key Elements of Post-Modern International Arbitration, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Lecture at McGeorge School of Law, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Lectures by Howard M. Holtzmann at a Plenary Session of the Legal Committee of the Hungarian Chamber of Commerce, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Leccture Notes, 1950s-1978 (Box 41, Folder 11-12)
    - Lecture Notes, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 13-14)
    - Lecture to Pre-Law Students, St. Bonaventure University, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Mass Claims Processes, 2002 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - "Mass Claims Settlements Procedures - Responding to New Circumstances" - Forward, 2005 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "Max Planck Encyclopedia of Public International Law" - "Mass Claims" Entry, 2005-2008 (Box 42, Folder 2-3)
    - "Mutual Cooperation Agreement between Permanent Court of Arbitration at the Hague and International Council for Commercial Arbitration", 1989 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "Neutrality of the Arbitrator - A Cultural Problem", 1989 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - New Look at Resolving Disputes in US-China Trade, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Notes, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Notes for Lecture on Resolving Mass Claims, 2002 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Papers/Speeches, 1981-1997 (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
    - The PCA and the Evolution of a Worldwide Arbitration Culture, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - The Peace Palace, Home of Arbitration, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Planning Efficient Arbitration Proceedings: The Accomplishments of Working Group I of the 1994 ICCA Vienna Congress, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - The Power of Parties to Choose and Exclude Applicable Law, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Politically Incorrect Bedtime Stories, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 7)